Hello, and welcome to Lesson 34 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
您好 欢迎来到 Wolfram U 的微积分入门课程第 34 课
The topic for this lesson is logarithmic functions.
本节课的课题是对数函数
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the subject.
我们先来简单介绍一下这个问题
In the last lesson, we talked about exponential functions
上节课 我们讲了指数函数
like this one, 2^x.
像这个 2^x
Here is a plot of the function.
下面是函数的图像
The question is suppose we want to solve the equation 2^x = 5.
问题是假设我们要解方程2^x=5
The problem here is that 5 is not a power of 2 in any obvious way,
这里的问题是 5显然不是2的幂
so we give it to Solve, and then Solve comes back and tells us
所以我们把它给Solve 然后Solve回来告诉我们
that x is Log[5]/Log[2].
即x为Log[5]/Log[2]
That’s the answer given by Solve, and really speaking,
这是Solve给出的答案 也是真正意义上的答案
it’s the logarithm of 5 to the base 2.
它是以2为底5的对数
That’s an example of a logarithm.
这就是一个对数的例子
This lesson will talk about these logarithmic functions
本课将更详细地讨论这些对数函数
in more detail and some of their properties.
及其一些特性
Basically,  a logarithm is an inverse function
基本上 对数是一个反函数
because it is the inverse of an exponential function a^x.
因为它是指数函数a^x的倒数
You can think of it as having the property that
你可以认为它具有以下特性
a raised to the logarithm of x to the base a is x,
a提高到x的对数 以a为基数就是x
and so is the logarithm of a^x in the base a.
所以是基数a^x的对数
The number a is the base of the logarithm.
数字a是对数的底数
Now we have a function called Log in the Wolfram Language
现在我们在Wolfram语言中有一个叫做Log的函数
which does these calculations.
它做这些计算
The log of 27 to the base 3 is 3 because 3^3 is 27,
以3为底27的对数是3 因为3^3是27
and the logarithm of 1/4^–2 is –2.
而1/4^-2的对数是-2
Keep in mind that the default base for Log is e,
请记住 Log的默认基数是e
so the logarithm of e^2 is just 2.
所以e^2的对数只是2
That’s the natural logarithm which is implemented
这是在 Wolfram 语言中
in the Wolfram Language with base e.
以 e 为基础实现的自然对数
Next let’s take the graph of a logarithm function.
接下来我们来看看对数函数的图形
Here’s the graph, and you’ll notice that it’s defined
这是它的图像 你会发现它
only for positive x, and the range is all the way from –∞ up to ∞.
只对正的x有定义 而且范围从-∞一直到∞
The function domain for the logarithm is just the positive numbers,
对数的函数域只是正数
and the range is all the real numbers.
而范围都是实数
Now if you look at the limits when x approaches ∞,
现在如果你看看当x接近∞时的极限
then you see that the answer is ∞, and when it approaches 0,
那么你就会发现 答案是∞ 而当它接近0时
the answer is –∞.
答案是-∞
Of course the graph intersects the x axis at x = 1.
当然 该图与x轴交于x=1
Okay. Next let’s take an example
好的接下来 我们以一个
where you have a base which is less than 1.
底数小于 1 的示例为例
Now the opposite happens.
现在却发生了相反的情况
You have a function which is still defined on positive numbers,
您有一个仍在正数上定义的函数
but it shoots up to ∞ at 0 and goes down to –∞ on the other side.
但它在0处射到∞ 另一侧则降到-∞
Domain and range is just the same as before,
定义域和值域和以前一样
but now the limits are the opposite,
但现在的极限是相反的
so when you approach ∞, you get –∞.
所以当你接近∞时 你会得到-∞
When you approach 0, you get ∞.
当你接近0时 你会得到∞
That’s the behavior of a logarithm whose base is less than 1.
这就是底数小于1的对数的行为
Finally, the plot has the same x intercept at x = 1.
最后 该图在x=1处有相同的x截距
Now the point is that when you have inverse functions,
现在的问题是 当你有反函数
then their graphs are reflections of each other in the line y = x.
那么它们的图形在y=x这条直线上是相互反映的
For example, if you take E^x and Log[x],
例如 如果取E^x和Log[x]
then they are inverse functions, and if you look at their graphs,
那么它们就是反函数 如果你看它们的图形
then they are reflections of each other in the line y = x.
那么它们在线段y=x中是相互反射的
Just the same happens if you take e^–x,
只是如果你把e^-x也是一样
and you see that again you have a reflection,
你看 你又有了反思
but that’s slightly harder to see.
但这稍微有点难看
The red plot is reflected in the line y = x to give you the blue plot.
红色图反映在线段y=x中 得到蓝色图
Now of course there are lots of properties
当然 现在有很多属性
of the exponential function,
指数函数的
and in just the same way, you have properties of the logarithm.
并且以同样的方式 你有对数的属性
So Log[x * y] is Log[x] + Log[y].
所以Log[x*y]就是Log[x]+Log[y]
But if you have quotients like x/y, then they turn into differences.
但如果你有像x/y这样的商 那么它们就会变成差
Finally if you have powers, then they turn into multiplication.
最后如果你有力量 那么它们就会变成乘法
The log of x^b is b times the log of x.
x^b的对数是b乘以x的对数
The point is that logarithms are really useful
重点是 对数真的很有用
because they convert multiplication to addition,
因为它们将乘法转化为加法
they convert division to subtraction
他们将除法转化为减法
and they convert powers to multiplication.
他们将幂数转化为乘法
Now an important rule is the change of base
现在一个重要的规则是基数的变化
where if you have a base x, you can change to base a
如果你有一个基数x 你可以改成基数a
by this kind of a quotient.
由这种商
The logarithm y to the base x is
对数y到基数x是
the logarithm of y to the base a
的对数 以y为基数a
divided by the logarithm of x to the base a.
除以x的对数 以a为基数
Okay. For example, when you get back this answer from Solve,
好的例如 当你从Solve得到这个答案时
then that really is the logarithm of 5 to the base 2.
那就真的是5的对数到2的基数
Okay. At long last, we can talk about
好了 终于 我们可以谈谈了最后 我们可以谈谈
the derivatives and integrals of logarithms.
对数的导数和积分；
The derivative for Log[x] is just 1/x.
Log[x]的导数只有1/x
That’s a very nice property, very surprising.
这是一个非常好的财产 非常令人惊讶
But the fact is that logarithms grow more slowly than polynomials.
但事实上 对数比多项式增长得更慢
Because you have a change of base formula,
因为你的基础公式发生了变化
you can work out the derivative of
你可以计算出
the logarithm of x to the base a as 1/(xLog[a]).
x对基数a的对数为1/(xLog[a])
You can apply the chain rule
您可以应用连锁规则
and work out more complicated derivatives.
并计算出更复杂的衍生产品
Here is a plot of the logarithm and its derivative.
这是一张对数及其导数的图
Notice that the logarithm function is only defined for positive x
请注意 对数函数只定义了正的x
whereas its derivative is defined for all x,
而它的导数是对所有x定义的
and that’s an issue which we’ll come back to later in the lesson.
而这个问题 我们在后面的课程中会再提到
How about the integral of log?
那对数的积分呢？
Well, the integral of log is xLog[x] – x,
那么 log的积分是xLog[x]-x
and that’s a bit hard to prove,
而这一点很难证明
but you can check the answer by doing a derivative,
但你可以通过做导数来检查答案
and you get back the usual function.
然后你就会回到通常的功能
The integral of the natural logarithm is xLog[x] – x.
自然对数的积分为xLog[x]-x
Here is a plot of the integral.
下面是积分图
Okay. Now an important application.
好了 现在是一个重要的应用现在 一个重要的应用
The integral of 1/x is possible to compute, but for that,
1/x的积分是可以计算的 但对于
you need to worry about the fact that the logarithm function
你需要担心的是 对数函数
is only defined for positive x whereas 1/x is defined for all x.
只定义了正的x 而1/x定义了所有x
To work out that difficulty, what we’ll do is we’ll introduce
为了解决这个难题 我们要做的是 我们将引入
a logarithm of the absolute value of x.
x的绝对值的对数
Now that’s nicely defined for all numbers, except of course for 0.
现在对所有的数字都有很好的定义 当然0除外
Once you have done that, then you can see that the integral of 1/x
一旦你做到了这一点 那么你可以看到1/x的积分
is the logarithm of the absolute value of x,
是x绝对值的对数
but in the Wolfram Language, the Log function
但在Wolfram语言中 日志函数
can handle both positive and negative numbers.
可以处理正数和负数
For example, the Log[–2] is the Log[2] plus a complex number.
例如 Log[-2]是Log[2]加上一个复数
So in the Wolfram Language, the integral of 1/x is just Log[x].
所以在Wolfram语言中 1/x的积分只是Log[x]
But in fact, one could write it as Log[|x|] + C.
但实际上 可以写成Log[|x|]+C
Okay. Finally, let’s talk about an application.
好吧 最后 我们来谈谈应用最后 我们来谈谈应用
Here is an exponential decay function.
这里是一个指数衰减函数
The n over here is a quantity at time t = 0, and the question is
这边的n是时间t=0时的量 问题是
how long would it take for the function
需要多长时间才能完成
to reach half of its initial value?
以达到其初始值的一半？
Well, to do that, we solve the equation and get back an answer,
好吧 要做到这一点 我们解方程 然后得到一个答案
and this answer is called the half-life of the function.
而这个答案叫做函数的半衰期
The λ is called the decay constant.
λ称为衰变常数
It tells you how fast it decays.
它告诉你它的衰减速度
1/λ is called the mean lifetime of the function.
1/λ称为函数的平均寿命
Often when you do such calculations,
通常当你进行这样的计算时
you will need to know the logarithm of 2.
你需要知道2的对数
The numerical value is approximately 0.693,
数值约为0.693
and that’s well worth memorizing.
这一点很值得记忆
With that, we come to the end of this lesson,
至此 我们来到了本节课的尾声
the main point being that logarithms are very useful
主要是对数很有用
in solving exponential equations of this type.
在解这类指数方程时
Just like you have properties of exponentials,
就像你有指数的属性一样
you also have properties of logarithms.
你也有对数的属性
The derivative of a logarithm of x is 1/x.
x的对数的导数为1/x
The integral is a lot harder.
积分的难度很大
It is xLog[x] – x + C.
它是xLog[x]-x+C
The integral of 1/x is Log[|x|] + C.
1/x的积分为Log[|x|]+C
Of course, you can use logarithms
当然 你也可以用对数
to find the half-life of a function.
以求函数的半衰期
That’s a brief introduction to logarithms—
这就是对数的简单介绍--
enough for us to now start talking about
足够让我们现在开始谈论
the so-called L’Hospital’s rule, which we’ll do next time.
所谓L'Hospital的规则 我们下次再做
I’ll stop over here. Thank you very much.
我在这里停一下谢谢你了